DAYS!
By the decision of Ying Zheng, the king that wished to unite all of China,
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
天下統一の道を行く王 嬴政(えいせい)のもと
秦国(しんこく)は 隣国 魏(ぎ)への侵攻を開始した
the State of Qin began its invasion of the neighboring State of Wei.
Wang Ben, Meng Tian, and Xin.
王賁(おうほん) 蒙恬(もうてん) そして信(しん)
未来の大将軍たらんとする兵(つわもの)が―
Three soldiers wishing to become Great Generals are gathered here
今ここに集い
新しき時代を迎えようとしていた
trying to usher in a new age.
蒙驁(もうごう)軍千人将たちを暗殺した輪虎(りんこ)は
Lun Hu, a man that assassinated several Thousand-Man Generals of the Meng Ao Army,
信との一騎打ちののち
風のごとく去った
disappeared into the wind after his one-on-one bout with Xin.
But the Meng Ao Army prepared for their next attack
しかし 蒙驁軍は 再びの襲来に備え
警戒の手を緩めることなく
進軍を続けていた
and continued their march with constant vigilance.
Midnight Great General
Xin.
（蒙恬）信
（信）うん？
Do you have a minute?
（蒙恬）ちょっといいか？
You, again? You sure stop by often.
また お前か… よく来んなぁ
（蒙恬）そんな顔するなよ
Don't make a face like that.
ちょっと気になってることが
あったから来たんだ
I was just a little concerned about something.
何だよ？
What is it?
The incidents of the officers getting slain,
この前の将校たちが討たれた件
もうさんざん上に聞かれただろうが
I'm hearing about it non-stop from higher ups.
お前なりに感じたことはなかったか
（信）感じたこと？
But have you sensed anything about it?
Sensed anything?
Yes. Such as how he was different from the other State of Wei soldiers we've seen thus far.
ああ 例えば これまでの魏国兵とは
どこか違ったとか
What was different about him?
どこか違ったっつうか…
（蒙恬）うん
“天が どうだ”とか―
Well, he was a geezer-brat that blathered on about the heavens and some weird shit like that.
なんか ワケの分かんねえこと言う
おっさんガキだったな
Geezer-brat?!
お… おっさんガキ？
しかも 三百人将かと思ったら
将軍だってよ アハハハッ！
Plus I thought he was a 300-Man General, but he turned out to be a Full General.
His name's Lun Hu or Loony Hu...
名は リンコだかニャンコだか
おいおい
将軍の名ぐらい覚えてろよ
Hey, hey, you should remember the name of a general.
まあ
名前は ともかく 強さは半端ねえし
Well, whatever his name is, his strength is really something.
俺と戦ったときも
本気出してなかったみてえだし
I don't think he was even being serious
when he fought with me.
He's completely different from the enemies I've fought before.
今までの敵とは 全く別物だ
Have you heard of General Lian Po?
廉頗(れんぱ)将軍のことは知っているか？
Lian Po?
廉頗？
ああ どっかの有名な将軍だな
Oh, that's some famous general, right?
確か 相当 強(つえ)えとか
I think I heard he was pretty strong.
ハァ… 強いなんてものじゃない
He's not just strong.
趙国(ちょうこく)元三大天(さんだいてん) 廉頗は
秦国六大将軍と同等の力の持ち主だ
Lian Po is a former member of the State of Zhao Three Great Devas,
a person possessing the same level of power as one of the State of Qin's Six Great Generals.
えっ！
廉頗って 三大天だったのか？
Lian Po's one of the Three Devas?!
Though now, Lian Po has defected to the State of Wei.
今 廉頗は魏国に亡命している
しかし 趙国の大将軍だった廉頗は
魏国 景湣王(けいびんおう)に信用されていない
But as he was a Great General of the State of Zhao,
he is not trusted by the King of the
State of Wei, King Jingmin.
Because of that, Lian Po hasn't been allowed to lead a State of Wei Army once in the three years since he defected.
故に 亡命してからの この３年間
廉頗は 一度も魏国軍を
率いることを許されなかった
All of China has recognized that Lian Po isn't coming back anymore,
廉頗は もう出てこないというのが
全中華の認識だけど
but what if that is all nonsense?
もし
それが全部 でたらめだとしたら？
If Lian Po getting a cold treatment is just a lie made up by the State of Wei,
つまり 廉頗が冷遇されていると
いうのが魏国のウソだとしたら―
we may be walking without proper caution into a place where a former Great Deva is lying in wait.
俺たちは
元三大天が待ち構えている所へ―
無警戒に
足を踏み入れていることになる
なっ！ そ… それは…
Th-That means...
（蒙武(もうぶ)）相変わらず
勘のよさだけは一人前だな
Your instincts are as excellent as always.
いっ！ も… 蒙武将軍
G-General Meng Wu!
Where are you going, Tian?
（蒙武）どこへ行く？ 恬
（蒙恬）ゲッ…
Oh, it's you, Father.
こ… これは父上　お久しぶりです
It's been quite some time.
You seem to be doing well.
お元気そうで何よりです
（信）えっ？
Father?
父上って… 親父(おやじ)… 親子！
You mean he's your dad?!
あら？ 言ってなかった？
（信）ハッ…
Oh? Didn't I tell you?
ぜ… 全然 似てねえ
（蒙恬）ハハハハッ…
You don't look a thing like him!
Hey, kid, what happened to Wang Qi's lance?
おい 小僧　王騎(おうき)の矛は どうした？
It's still a little too heavy for me.
俺には まだ ちょっと重すぎる
Xin has Wang Qi's lance?!
信が王騎の矛を？
フン… 一生 使えそうにないなら
俺が もらってやるぞ
If you don't think you'll ever use it, I'll take it off your hands.
Yeah, right!
誰が
By the way Father, what brings you to a place like this?
ところで 父上
何用で こんな所に？
I thought you weren't participating in this war.
確か
こたびは参戦しないはずでは？
I'm here substituting for Changpingjun's messenger.
昌平君(しょうへいくん)の伝者代わりよ
内容は
先ほど お前が言っていたとおりだ
It's about what I told you previously.
Xin, the general you fought was without a doubt one of Lian Po's subordinates.
信 お前が戦った将軍というのは
間違いなく廉頗の手の者だ
Guess so.
だろうな
（蒙恬）俺たちは 既に―
We're already playing into Lian Po's hands.
廉頗の策にハマっている
Yeah, but if our enemy is a former Great Deva,
だが 敵が元三大天だとしたら
なおのこと負けるわけにゃいかねえ
that's all the more reason we can't let him win!
Might I ask something, my lord?
（姜燕(きょうえん)）よろしいですか？ 殿
（廉頗）何じゃ？
What is it?
There is one thing I do not understand.
ひとつ 腑(ふ)に落ちぬことが
The motive?
動機か…
Yes.
はい
Why is it that after staying silent for three years, you suddenly rose up again, my lord?
なぜ ３年間 沈黙されていた殿が
今 急に立ち上がられたのかと
唆されておったのよ
３年前 あやつにな
I was enticed by that guy three years ago.
あやつ …とは？
"That guy", sir?
One of the State of Xin Great Generals, Wang Qi.
秦国六大将軍 王騎じゃ
I could not forget.
忘れもしませぬ　３年前といえば
我々が魏国に亡命した年
Three years ago was the year we
defected to the State of Wei.
But what do you mean you were enticed by Wang Qi?
しかし
あの王騎に唆されていたとは？
Oh? You didn't know that back then, he was
communicating with the States of Wei and Zhao?
そうか　うぬは あのころ
魏国 趙国を往来して 知らなんだか
王騎から 何か書簡のような物が？
Did you have some letter correspondence with Wang Qi?
ハハハッ… 書簡ではない
It wasn't with letters.
王騎本人が現れたのじゃ
Wang Qi himself showed up.
To my mansion in the State of Wei.
魏国で
あてがわれた わしの屋敷にな
Wang Qi...
（廉頗）王騎
You're somebody...
貴様というヤツは―
who always, always...
いつも いつも…
gets me excited.
わしをシビれさせるのぅ
My greatest sympathies for all this strife.
（王騎）こたびの騒動
心中 お察しいたします
One of the State of Qin
Wang Qi
Six Great Generals
（廉頗）よく来てくれた！
Glad to have you here!
さあ 上がれ
出陣前のように酒を用意した
Come, step right up!
I've prepared some pre-campaign liquor!
10日や そこらでは帰さぬぞ
ハハハハッ！
You won't be heading home for around ten days!
（王騎）ココココッ… ありがたく
Thank you.
Wang Qi had heard I had defected from Wei to Zhao so he went out of his way to cross the state border to come visit.
（廉頗）王騎は 趙国を出て
魏国に亡命した わしを見舞いに
わざわざ
国境を越えて やってきたのじゃ
I heard that on his way, he poked his head into a battle between Wu Qing and Biao Gong,
来る途中 呉慶(ごけい)と麃公(ひょうこう)の戦いに
首を突っ込んだと聞き
王騎の来訪は
秘密にせねばならなかったがな
though he had to keep his visit a secret.
I am quite surprised.
驚きました
しかし それは さぞかし―
But you certainly...
must have been delighted.
うれしゅうございましたな
Yes. Enough to bring tears to my eyes.
ああ 涙が出るほどにな
というより―
Or rather, he actually did make me cry quite a few times.
実際 何度か泣かされたわい
ハハハハッ…
In contrast to how Great Deva Ling Giangru and I would risk our necks with no regrets for each other,
互いのためなら
首を懸けても悔いのない友が―
三大天の藺相如(りんしょうじょ)だとするならば
王騎ら六大将軍は 死ぬほど
憎らしい最大の敵でありながら
Wang Qi and the other Six Great Generals were my fervently hated enemies.
But somewhere deep down, we were friends that knew each others pain and joy.
どこかで 苦しみと喜びを
分かち合っている友であった
That's why when the Six Great General Chief, Bai Qi, killed himself, I wept.
だから 六大将軍筆頭の白起(はくき)が
自害したときには 涙を流し
摎(きょう)が どこぞの輩(やから)に討たれたときは
怒りに震えた
When Liao was killed by some lot, I shook with rage.
So, how is it Wang Qi enticed you then?
して 殿は そのとき
王騎に どう唆されたのです？
The world of excitement that makes the blood tingle is already a thing of the past.
血湧き 肉躍る世界
それは 既に過去のもの
誠に退屈です
Honestly, it's become boring.
General, I well understand your lamentation.
将軍 あなたの嘆き
私には よく理解できますよ
But General, if you ever have a time to stand again,
ですが 将軍
あなたが もし立つときがあったら
do try doing battle with the Meng Ao Army.
蒙驁軍と戦ってごらんなさい
That may distract you from your boredom.
退屈が紛れますよ
（廉頗）ンンッ…
Meng Ao?
蒙驁 …というと―
That mediocre general?
あの凡庸な将軍のことですか？
（廉頗）凡庸？
Mediocre?
Yep, that's right!
確かに そのとおりじゃ ハハハッ！
L-Lian Po has reemerged?!
（土門(どもん)）
れ… 廉頗が出てくるですと！
（栄備(えいび)）
マズイことになったな 土門将軍
This is quite troubling, General Tu Men.
If he's guarding a castle, it's unassailable.
ヤツが城を守ったならば不落となる
あの白起将軍ですら 廉頗からは…
（蒙武）ンンッ…
Even General Bai Qi couldn't capture one from Lian Po...
Now, now. This isn't something to be so flustered about.
（蒙驁）これこれ
そう慌てることもなかろうて
The appearance of Lian Po is not beyond our expectations.
廉頗の出現は
想定外のことではない
副将たちとも
初めから 対応策を練っておるわい
I have been concocting countermeasures against him with the Vice Generals from the beginning.
フォフォ… せがれや
よく伝えに来てくれたのぅ
Thank you for bringing us this news, son.
Knowing so far in advance will allow us to carefully erect a strategy.
早めに知ったおかげで わしらは
ゆっくり作戦を立てられる
今日の軍議は長引きそうじゃ
I expect today's war council to be a long one.
Maybe I'll pick out some liquor to bring.
酒を選んでくるかのぅ
フォフォフォ…
That's our lord. Hearing Lian Po's name did not shake him in the least.
（土門）さすがは殿だ
廉頗の名にも 全く動じておらぬ
（蒙驁）ハァ…
廉頗が出おった…
Lian Po showed up...
It was... a bluff?!
（側近１）ハッタリ …ですと？
Yes.
ああ
（側近１）大殿が？
The Great General was...
（側近２）
そうは見えませんでしたが
It didn't seem like it, though.
This will not be my father's first time fighting Lian Po.
親父が廉頗と戦うのは
初めてではない
What? That shouldn't be...
はぁ？ いや そんなはずは…
親父も俺も もともと斉国(せいこく)の
人間だったことは知っているな？
You know that Father and I were originally from the State of Qi, yes?
は… はい それは
Y-Yes, we know...
親父は 廉頗と同じ世代で
駆け出しの若造のころから―
My father is from the same generation as Lian Po, and ever since they were young novices,
幾度となく
斉国 趙国の戦で やり合っている
they fought on countless occasions in the states of Qi and Zhao.
And he did not defeat Lian Po a single time.
そして
廉頗に勝ったことは一度としてない
なっ…
（側近２）そ… そんな…
Wh-What?!
故に
親父は斉国での武将の道を閉ざされ
Because of that, my father's path as a military general in the State of Qi was cut off for him.
So when I was a child, he was forced to bring us to the State of Qin.
ガキの俺を連れて
秦国に流れるハメになった
親父は 秦国に移って
ようやく花を咲かせたが
After my father moved to the State of Qin, his flower finally blossomed.
それから 廉頗とは対戦していない
But he has not fought Lian Po since then.
フン… 恐らく―
It's likely that Lian Po does not remember fighting my father in his youth.
廉頗は 若いころに親父と
戦ったことなど覚えておるまい
廉頗とは―
But for my father, Lian Po is a wall that he could never overcome no matter how he tried.
親父にとって どうしても
超えられなかった大きな壁なのだ
Meng Tian
Meng Ao has an odd habit.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
蒙驁には 不思議な癖がある
When he is under heavy mental pressure, this man takes off his Great General armor,
大きな精神的圧迫を受けたとき
この男は 大将軍の甲冑(かっちゅう)を脱ぎ置き
disguises himself as a dirty old soldier, and wanders around the encampment.
汚い老人歩兵に化けて
陣内を徘徊(はいかい)するのである
And afterwards, he lays out on a quiet meadow and simply empties his mind.
そして 最後は―
静かな草原に 身を投げ出して
ただ 頭の中を空っぽにする
But that day...
だが その日は…
Lian Po... Why would he come now?
廉頗… なぜヤツが今ごろ
But... this moon sure is...
しかし…
ふむ この月は なかなか…
（信）しゃ！ 夜食だ 夜食！
All right! Midnight snack!
Sorry I stepped on ya.
悪かったな 踏んづけちまって
鼻血 止まったか？
Your nose stop bleeding?
Just sit tight, I'll give you a little something to eat.
待ってな　少し食わせてやっから
Did you catch that rabbit?
そのウサギ お前が捕まえたのか？
おうよ　夜食だよ 夜食
Yeah. It's my midnight snack.
The rations aren't enough to fill my stomach.
配給だけじゃ
腹いっぱいになんねえかんな
上の連中は ホント
ケチくせえぜ　なっ？ じいさん
Those higher-ups sure are stingy bastards, ain't they, Gramps?
Here.
ほらよ
（蒙驁）おお…
いっ！ …つうか
じいさん ものすげえ でけえな
Hey, Gramps, you're freakin' huge, ain'cha?!
何者(なにもん)だ？ ヒゲも すげえぞ
（蒙驁）フォフォ…
Who are you?! Your beard's awesome, too!
That's weird. I don't remember seein' a huge geezer soldier like you.
おかしいな… そんな でけえ
じいさん歩兵 見たことなかったぞ
フォフォ… そうか？
Really?
It's my first time seeing a youngster soldier like you as well.
おぬしのほうこそ
どこの小僧歩兵じゃ？
初めて見たぞい
（信）小僧歩兵じゃねえよ
I'm no youngster soldier.
飛信隊の信
れっきとした三百人将だぜ
I'm Xin of the Feixin Unit.
A full-fledged 300-Man General.
うん？ 飛信隊？
確か 王騎が名付け親の特殊部隊
Feixin Unit...
Isn't that the special unit that Wang Qi named?
I see. So this boy is the Xin of the Feixin unit that received Wang Qi's lance.
そうか　この子が
王騎の矛を受け取った飛信隊の信
うめえ！
Yum!
So, what're you doin' around here?
…で こんな所で何してんだ？
う… う～む… そうじゃのぅ
Hm, well...
Just trying to escape reality for a bit.
軽く現実逃避をじゃな…
（信）ハハハッ！ 何だ？ それ
Heh. What's with that?
So you still get worried even when you're an old geezer?
…てか じいさんにもなって
悩みなんか あんのか？
Sure we do.
そりゃあるわい
年季が入っている分 深刻じゃぞ
And it's more serious the longer your service time.
Tell me about it.
ハハッ… 言ってみ
三百人将が聞いてやる
This 300-Man General here is listening.
I see. Maybe I'll tell you, then.
そうじゃのぅ
それでは聞いてもらおうかのぅ
In my younger days, there was an opponent I never beat even once.
若いころに ケンカで一度も
勝てなかった相手がいたとする
うんうん ありがちだ
Yeah, that happens a lot.
そして じじいになった今
And now that I'm an old geezer,
なんと その相手と
もう一度 ケンカすることになった
it looks like I'm going to fight that opponent once again.
And rather than getting old and decrepit,
しかも 相手は老いるどころか 逆に
脂の乗りきった絶頂期と来ておる
he's at the peak of his prime right now.
そのじじい すんげえな
じじいで絶頂期って
That geezer sounds awesome.
To peak as an old man.
Yep. He's a monster.
うむ… バケモノじゃ
（信）ふ～ん…
フォフォフォ… 深刻じゃろう？
Doesn't that sound serious?
You've still gotta fight monsters even as an old man?
じいさんにまでなって
バケモノと戦うか　う～ん…
悩む意味が 全然 分からん
むしろ やったじゃねえか
I really don't get what you're worried about.
In fact, this sounds pretty sweet.
うん？ 小僧 人の話を
ちゃんと聞いておったのか？
Youngster... were you even listening to me?
I was listenin'!
聞いてたよ
全敗喫してるバケモノじじいと―
You said you've got another chance to fight the monster old geezer you lost to every time before.
もう１回
じいさんがやるって話だろう？
That sounds pretty good to me!
やっぱり やったじゃねえか
I still don't see what's so good!
だから 何がやったんじゃ？
You know, I'm sayin' that with this time, you've got a chance to turn it around in one shot, right?!
だって それは この期に及んで―
じいさんに 一発逆転の好機が
生まれたって話だろう？
In a fight, the one standing at the end is the winner.
ケンカってのは
最後に立ってたヤツの勝ちだ
次 勝って 勝ち逃げしてやれよ
So win next time and then quit while you're ahead!
Then you'll be the overall winner!
そうすりゃ じいさんの総勝ちだ！
ふむ… フォ…
フハハハッ！
（信）ウオッ… びっくりした
You scared me there!
You know, you've got a point, Lord Captain.
確かに そのとおりじゃ 隊長どの
次に勝てば 一発逆転
わしの勝ちじゃ フォフォフォ！
If I win next time it'll turn the tables and I'll be the winner!
フォフォフォ！
（信）お… おう
Yeah.
やったれ じいさん！
You can do it, Gramps!
As you know, in the recent attacks
（郭叫(かくきょう)）
知ってのとおり 先の急襲により
our army has lost Thousand-Man Generals.
我が軍は 千人将を失った
その部隊については副将の繰り上げ
So to deal with the losses, we will be moving up the Vice Captains of those units
もしくは 隊を解体して
ほかの増兵に回し 対処する
or we will be breaking the units up and adding them to other units!
Lord Xin, you should listen to this.
（渕(えん)）
信どの ちゃんと聞いてください…
（あくび）
（郭叫）しかし今
But now we have two empty seats of Thousand-Man Generals.
（郭叫）２つの千人将の席が
空白のままである　故に―
Therefore...
we will temporarily be promoting two 300-Man Generals to the rank of Thousand-Man Generals!
三百人将を２人 臨時で
千人将へ昇格させることとなった
Did he just...
（尾平(びへい)）えっ？ 今…
（田有(でんゆう)）三百人将を せ… 千人将に
昇格させるって言ったぞ
He said he was promoting 300-Man Generals to Thousand-Man Generals!
すげえぞ 信 こりゃ！
Xin, this is incredible!
W-Wait a minute.
（去亥(きょがい)）い… いや ちょっと待て
今 確か 昇格させる三百人将は―
Didn't he just say that there would only be two 300-Man Generals promoted?
２人だって…
What do you think, Qiang Lei?
どう思う？ 羌瘣(きょうかい)
If you think about it reasonably, it will be Wang Ben and Meng Tian...
（羌瘣）
順当に考えれば 王賁 蒙恬の２人
Hey, what's with that?!
（田永(でんえい)）おい！ 何だよ そりゃ！
We will now announce them!
発表する
The first is...
まず１人目は…
楽華(がくか)隊の蒙恬！
そなたを千人将に昇格させる
Meng Tian of the Yuehua Unit!
You are promoted to Thousand-Man General!
You will be given 700 soldiers, making the Yuehua Unit a Thousand-Man Unit!
700人増兵し 楽華隊を千人隊とする
（じい）
やりましたな 蒙恬さま ようやく…
We really did it, Lord Meng Tian!
Finally...
う～ん… ちょっと複雑
I'm not sure how I feel about it.
蒙恬…
Meng Tian...
You can't blame them. They say Meng Tian was considered to have the rank of a Thousand-Man General to begin with.
しかたがないだろう
蒙恬は本来 千人将の位という話だ
Y-Yeah.
So then... who's the other one?
となると―
もう１人は…
Moving on, the second of the two 300-Man Generals being promoted to Thousand-Man General is...
（郭叫）続いて２人目　もう１人
千人将に昇格する三百人将は…
Wang Ben of the Yufeng Unit!
玉鳳(ぎょくほう)隊の王賁！
（番陽(ばんよう)）ウハハハッ！
In every sense, it's natural that Lord Ben would be the one chosen.
あらゆる意味で
賁さまが選ばれるのは当然のこと
Damn, it was them after all.
クッ… やっぱり あいつらか
They had some huge achievements rendered
ヤツらのほうが 上げた武功は
でかかったし そもそも―
and to begin with, they're from a noble family.
名門の出だ
Are you all right, Lord Xin?
大丈夫ですか？ 信どの
（信）ンンッ… 俺は…
I...
俺は… ンンッ…
Lord Xin.
信どの…
信…
（田有）隊長…
Xin.
Captain.
Now then, dismissed!
それでは 解散！
（蒙驁）待て
Wait.
Ah, my lord? What is it?
（土門）殿… 何か？
Xin of the Feixin Unit, forward.
飛信隊の信 前へ！
（どよめき）
信どの 将軍が呼んでいます
Lord XIn, the general is calling you.
Lord Xin!
信どの
（信）あ… ああ
R-Right.
General Meng Ao is... calling me?
あの蒙驁将軍が 俺を呼んだ？
フォ…
What?! The old man from last night...
ゆ… ゆうべの じいさ…
（蒙驁）フォフォフォ…
When considering your skill, Xin of the Feixin Unit,
飛信隊 信の
力量について考えるとき
your achievements on this campaign paled compared to Meng Tian's and Wang Ben's.
こたびの遠征での武功は 確かに
蒙恬 王賁 両人には見劣りする
But considering your achievements in the previous war with the State of Zhao,
じゃが
先の趙国との戦の功まで考えるなら
三百人将以上の力があることは
十分 示されている
you clearly displayed strength greater than that of a 300-Man General.
Enough to say we should establish a seat for one more Thousand-Man General.
つまり もうひとつ千人将の席を
設けてやる価値はあると言える
P-Please, wait, General.
（郭叫）お… お待ちください 将軍
千人将が必要なら
ほかにも まだ候補が…
If we need another Thousand-Man General, then we have many other candidates.
And with that one, we have the problem of his origins as a servant...
それに
その者は 下僕の出という問題も…
What about that is a problem?
それの どこが問題じゃ？
（郭叫）あっ… い… いえ
I-It's nothing.
Anyhow, this is a whim of mine.
…とはいえ これは わしの気まぐれ
独断である
It's a decision at my own discretion.
If you accept this promotion, there will of course be great animosity from those around you.
この昇格を受ければ 当然
周りの反感を大いに買うじゃろう
従って それらを黙らせるためにも
Therefore, in order to silence those voices,
昇格には
厳しい条件をつけねばならん
I must attach a harsh condition to your promotion.
Harsh condition?
（信）厳しい条件？
The heads of enemy generals.
敵将の首じゃ
At least three Thousand-Man Generals.
千人将なら３つ以上 将軍なら
１つ以上の首を挙げてもらう
Or at least one Full General.
落とせなかった場合は―
But if you fail to do so...
you'll be demoted three ranks and you'll have to start over from Wu Chief.
３段階降格し
伍長(ごちょう)から やり直しとする
（信）えっ…
（蒙驁）つまり―
In other words, if you fail,
失敗した場合 飛信隊は解散となる
the Feixin Unit will be disbanded.
So, what do you say? Do you still accept, Xin of the Feixin Unit?
どうじゃ？ それでも受けるか？
飛信隊の信
だから 言ってんだろう　そんなの
悩む所じゃねえって じいさん
I told you, didn't I?
That's nothing to be worried about, Gramps!
How rude! How dare you speak to the lord in such a manner!
（李充(りじゅう)）無礼な！ 殿に向かって
その口の利き方は何だ！
（蒙驁）フォ…
People who step away because they're scared of failing
失敗が怖(こえ)えからって
後ずさりするヤツは―
should just stay holed up in their houses to begin with.
最初から
家に閉じこもってりゃいいんだ
伍長から やり直し？
Restart from Wu Chief?!
ダメだったら いちばん下っ端の
歩兵から やり直してやるよ
If I screw up, then I'll start back from the lowest-ranked foot soldier!
And what's more, I'm not thinking about some little thing like the head of one general.
それによ
俺は 将軍の首ひとつなんて
みみっちいことは考えてねえぞ
フォ？
What Xin and the Feixin Unit have their sights on is...
飛信隊 信が狙うのは
敵総大将 廉頗の首だ！
is the head of the enemy Supreme Commander, Lian Po!
（蒙驁）うむ… よかろう
Very well, then!
Xin of the Feixin Unit!
飛信隊 信
そなたを千人将に昇格させる
I hereby promote you to Thousand-Man General!
Therefore the Feixin Unit will gain 700 men,
（蒙驁）
よって 飛信隊は700人増兵し
becoming a Thousand-Man Unit!
千人隊とする
ハハッ… ウワッ！
やったぜ！ いてっ…
That kid's a Thousand-Man General...
あの小僧が千人将…
確かに力はあるでしょうが
まだ子供　大丈夫でしょうか？
He's definitely strong, but he's still a kid... Is this really a good idea?
Compared to other Great Generals, Father has less military talent.
（蒙武）親父は ほかの大将軍に
比べて 軍事上の才は劣るが
But in exchange, his eye for people is unparalleled under the heavens.
しかし その分
人を見る目は 天下に比類ない
So if my father recommends him, I have no problems.
その親父が推すのであれば
問題ないであろう
Preview
The Night Before
the Start of the War
End